this exercise
asks us to write a program that checks
if the sequence of
characters lab or lab
exists in the following strings and
we've been given five strings
if the sequence of characters does exist
we want to print the word out
we can accomplish this using regex and
to explore that a little bit
let's jump into irb so
the pattern we want to match
is the sequence of characters lab
and we can use the regex match operator
let's check this pattern against the
string laboratory first
now looking at the documentation for
this regex match operator
we can see that it will return either an
integer
or nil let's see what's returned when we
run this code
0 is returned 0 is the index at which
that match begins
if we instead check the string elaborate
we'll see a different integer returned
this time we see one because that
sequence of characters begins at index
one
now what happens if we check the string
experiment
you can see that we don't expect a match
here
and nil is returned so
let's hop into our code editor
we can write a method let's call it
check in and we'll pass in the word
that we want to check
and we know that we can use this regex
to check for a match in word as we saw
this code is going to return either an
integer
which is truthy or nil which is falsey
and because of this we can easily use an
if statement here
if there is a match our condition will
be truthy
and line three will be executed so in
that case
we want to output the word with put s
if there's no match and nil is returned
the else branch of our if statement will
be executed
in that case let's just output
no match
let's test this out
we'll invoke our check check-in method
with the string laboratory
and we expect that this will output the
string laboratory
because it is a match
and it does
now let's run our method with the other
four strings passed in as arguments
so when we run our code we see that
laboratory and elaborate
did contain the sequence of characters
so those strings were output
the other three strings did not contain
the sequence of characters
and so no match was output
now there's one interesting thing to
note here which is that
labyrinth did not produce a match to our
sequence of characters
and that's because the l in labyrinth is
uppercase
and our sequence of characters is
specifically looking for
a lowercase l for case insensitive
matches
we can use the i option with our regex
now when we run our code we'll see three
matches
and that's what we see